Now that we're getting to more complex queries using Subqueries,
والآن بعد أن نتناول استعلامات أكثر تعقيدًا باستخدام استعلامات فرعية،
the classroom workspace may seem a bit cramped.
قد تبدو مساحة العمل في الفصل الدراسي متكدسة.
If you've not already been writing your queries in an editor,
إذا لم تكونوا تكتبون استعلاماتكم في محرر،
now is a great time to start. Here's my workflow.
فقد حان الوقت لتبدؤوا في ذلك. ها هو سير العمل.
You can see over here on the left,
يمكنكم أن تروا هنا على اليسار،
I have my editor open with the subqueries.sql extension.
لقد فتحت محرري بالامتداد subqueries.sql.
And then over here on the right, is the classroom,
وهنا على اليمين، الفصل الدراسي،
where I can read the questions and execute my code.
حيث يمكنني قراءة الأسئلة وتنفيذ الكود.
So, now let's take a look at this first question.
والآن، لنلقِ نظرة على السؤال الأول.
It says provide the name of the sales rep in
وهو يقول اذكر اسم مندوب المبيعات في
each region with the largest amount of total USD sales.
كل منطقة بها أكبر قدر من إجمالي المبيعات بالدولار الأمريكي.
In order to solve this problem,
ولحل هذه المسألة،
let's first try to pull some of this information together.
لنجرب أولًا سحب بعض المعلومات معًا.
We can see that the sales rep information exists in this table.
ويمكننا أن نرى أن معلومات مندوب المبيعات موجودة في هذا الجدول.
The region information is over here,
ومعلومات المنطقة موجودة هنا،
and the total amount USD is over here in the orders table.
وإجمالي مبلغ الدولارات الأمريكية هنا في جدول الطلبات.
Therefore we need to join these four tables
ومن ثم، نحتاج إلى ربط هذه الجداول الأربعة
together in order to pull all this information together.
معًا لسحب هذه المعلومات معًا.
So, let's go ahead and start.
حسنًا، لنتابع ونبدأ.
Start with a comment.
ابدؤوا بتعليق.
Okay, so that should
حسنًا، يجب أن يسهل هذا
make it easier to find that stuff when I come back.
إيجاد هذا الأمر عندما أعود.
And let's go ahead and start tackling this problem.
فلنبدأ في معالجة هذه المسألة.
So, we want to pool all this information together.
حسنًا، نريد جمع هذه المعلومات كلها معًا.
So, let's go ahead and start with the sales rep table.
فلنتابع ونبدأ بجدول مندوبي المبيعات.
I'll label that with an alias of SR. Let's join the region table,
وسأسمي هذا بالاسم المستعار SR. فلنربط جدول المنطقة،
I'll label that with an alias of R. We want to
وسأسمي هذا بالاسم المستعار R.
join this where the primary and foreign keys match,
نريد أن نربط هذا عند مطابقة المفاتيح الغريبة والأساسية،
and so therefore that's just like SR region ID is equal to r.id.
ومن ثم، يبدو هذا كأن معرف منطقة SR يساوي معرف r.id.
And then if we want to pull the accounts information,
وإذا كنا نريد سحب معلومات الحسابات،
I'll have an alias of A and we want a sales rep id equal to sr.id.
سيكون لديّ الاسم المستعار A ونريد أن يكون معرف مندوب المبيعات مساويًا لمعرف sr.id.
And then let's join the orders table and we'll join now
والآن لنربط جدول الطلبات وسنربط الآن
on o.account id equal to a.id.
على معرّف الحساب o مساوٍ لمعرف a.id.
Cool. So, now we sort of have all of our information pulled together.
رائع. يبدو أن لدينا الآن جميع المعلومات المسحوبة معًا.
We can see from the query we're going to need the name of the sales rep,
يمكننا أن نرى من الاستعلام أننا سنحتاج إلى اسم مندوب المبيعات،
the region, and then the total amount of sales for each of these reps.
والمنطقة ثم إجمالي مبلغ المبيعات لكلٍ من هؤلاء المندوبين.
So, let's go ahead and just pull some of that information together.
حسنًا، فلنتابع ونسحب بعض هذه المعلومات معًا.
So, if we pull the sales rep information,
إذًا، إذا سحبنا معلومات مندوب المبيعات،
and then we can pull the region information,
يمكننا سحب معلومات عن المنطقة،
and then the orders.
ثم الطلبات.
We want the total amount,
نريد إجمالي المبلغ،
and we need that basically for each rep we want.
ونحتاج إلى ذلك بشكل أساسي لكل مندوب نريده.
The sum of this. So, let's just call that total sales.
مجموع هذا. حسنًا لنقل إن هذا إجمالي المبيعات.
And then we're going to want to group by the things that aren't in our alias.
ثم سنحتاج إلى التجميع حسب الأشياء غير الموجودة في الاسم المستعار.
So, our alias is right here,
حسنًا ها هو الاسم المستعار،
and we have these two columns that are outside of it.
ولدينا هذان العمودان الموجودان خارجه.
I'll just do One comma two,
وسأكتب واحد فاصلة اثنين،
and we might do an order by the third descending let's say.
وقد نرتبها من الثالث تنازليًا.
Let's go ahead and run this,
لنتابع ونشغِّل هذا،
see what we get.
انظروا ما سنحصل عليه.
Cool.
رائع.
So, it looks like that executed.
إذًا، يبدو أنه تم تنفيذ ذلك.
You can see we only got one name column back,
يمكنكم أن تروا أن لدينا عمود اسم واحد فقط،
and that's probably because,
وربما يكون هذا بسبب،
the workspace is confused about having these two columns named the same thing.
اضطراب مساحة العمل بخصوص وجود هذين العمودين اللذين لهما الاسم ذاته.
So, let's be more explicit.
إذًا لنكن صرحاء أكثر.
Let's just call this rep, name, and region.
فلنسمِ هذا المندوب، والاسم، والمنطقة.
Let's try that again.
ولنجرب هذا مجددًا.
Cool.
رائع.
So, now we got three of them.
حسنًا، لدينا الآن ثلاثة أعمدة.
We have the rep, the region, and the total sales.
لدينا المندوب والمنطقة وإجمالي المبيعات.
But for this question,
ولكن لهذا السؤال،
we want to provide the name of the sales rep in
نريد توفير اسم مندوب المبيعات في
each region with the largest amount of total sales.
كل منطقة الذي حقق أكبر قدر من إجمالي المبيعات.
So basically, what we want for the Southeast region is we want
أساسًا ما نريده للمنطقة الجنوبية الشرقية هو أننا نريد
this individual for the Northeast region we want this individual,
هذا الفرد وللمنطقة الشمالية الشرقية نريد هذا الفرد،
but here we have
ولكن هنا لدينا
another Southeast region person we don't want them showing up in our table.
شخص آخر من المنطقة الجنوبية الشرقية لا نريده أن يظهر في جدولنا.
This person should be for the West,
يجب أن يكون هذا الشخص في المنطقة الغربية،
and then any other regions that we have we basically just want that top individual.
ثم في أي مناطق أخرى أردنا أن يكون فيها ذلك الشخص بشكل أساسي.
So, in order to do this,
إذًا لنقم بهذا،
we're going to have to do a tricky join,
سيكون علينا إجراء ربط مخادع،
but this is pretty common.
ولكنه أمر شائع.
Basically, we have the information from this table and we like that.
في الأساس، لدينا معلومات من هذا الجدول ويعجبنا ذلك.
So we're going to create a subquery.
إذًا، سننشئ استعلامًا فرعيًا.
And I'm just going to call this t1.
سأطلق على هذا اسم t1.
We could probably come up with a better naming convention for that.
ربما نأتي بمصطلح أفضل لتسمية لذلك.
But, we want to pull from t1 and then basically what we want to do,
لكن نريد السحب من t1 ثم في الأساس ما نريد فعله
is we want to select the region.
هو أننا نريد تحديد المنطقة.
So, for each region we just want the maximum total sales.
حسنًا لا نريد سوى سحب أقصى إجمالي مبيعات لكل منطقة.
So, from this table that we just looked at that one exists right here,
حسنًا، من هذا الجدول الذي شاهدناه للتو، ذلك الموجود هنا،
we're going to pull the region along with the max total sales for that region.
سنسحب المنطقة مع أقصى إجمالي مبيعات لتلك المنطقة.
And because this is already grouped by the individual,
ونظرًا لأن هذا تم تجميعه بالفعل حسب الفرد،
we're just going to get the max number over here for each region.
سنحصل على أقصى رقم هنا لكل منطقة.
So, for Southeast that should just pull this number,
حسنًا، يجب سحب هذا الرقم للجنوب الشرقي،
and for Northeast it should just pull this number.
ويجب سحب هذا الرقم للشمال الشرقي.
And for the West,
وبالنسبة للغرب،
it should pull this number and then it'll keep looking.
يجب سحب هذا الرقم وهكذا.
And then you can see we have this Northeast region,
من ثم يمكنكم أن تروا أن لدينا المنطقة الشمالية الشرقية هذه،
and so it should just pull this max one,
وبالتالي يجب سحب الحد الأقصى هذا،
and all the rest of these should go away.
ويجب أن يختفي كل ما يتبقى.
Unfortunately, we can't do this all at once,
لسوء الحظ، لا يمكننا إجراء كل هذا مرة واحدة،
because if we group by the individual again,
لأننا إذا جمعنا حسب الفرد مرة أخرى،
the individual along with the region is still
فلا يزال الفرد مع المنطقة
unique so we'd end up with all of these table values back.
فريدًا وبالتالي سننتهي بجميع هذه القيم في الجدول مرة أخرى.
But if we grew by just the region, and we pull the max,
ولكن إذا طورنا حسب المنطقة فقط وسحبنا الحد الأقصى،
we should only get the one rep with the maximum amount of sales.
فيجب علينا فقط الحصول على مندوب واحد مع أقصى قدر من المبيعات.
So, that's what we're going to do in this table.
حسنًا، هذا ما سنفعله في هذا الجدول.
So, this is the max sales for the region because we have another aggregate up here,
إذًا، هذا أقصى مبيعات للمنطقة لأن لدينا تجميعًا آخر في الأعلى هنا،
we're going to need to group by anything that's not in the aggregate.
سنحتاج إلى التجميع حسب أي شيء غير موجود في التجميع.
So, it's just this first thing.
إذًا هذا هو الأمر الأول.
Well let's go ahead and run this, make sure that it works.
حسنًا، لنتابع ونشغِّل هذا مع التأكد من أنه يعمل.
Cool. So, now what you're seeing is we have these four regions,
رائع. ما تروه الآن هو أن لدينا هذه المناطق الأربعة،
and I think I said the wrong thing about the Northeast earlier.
وأعتقد أنني قلت أمرًا خطأ عن الشمال الشرقي من قبل.
We have these four regions each with their max sales,
لدينا هذه المناطق الأربعة في كلٍ منها أقصى مبيعات،
and essentially what we want to do is we want to match that back to the original table.
وبالضرورة ما نريد فعله هو أننا نريد مطابقة هذا الجدول بالجدول الأصلي.
We want to match that to the table that we had before,
نريد مطابقة ذلك بالجدول الذي كان لدينا من قبل،
where the regions match as well as where the total sales,
حيث تتطابق المناطق وحيث يساوي إجمالي المبيعات
is equal to the max sales.
أقصى مبيعات.
So, let's go ahead and do that.
إذًا لنتابع ونفعل هذا.
So, we have this table,
حسنًا، لدينا هذا الجدول،
that's this one that exists over here on the right now.
هذا هو الذي يوجد هنا على اليمين الآن.
So, we're going to take that and we'll just,
حسنًا، سنأخذ هذا،
again I'm just going to call it T2.
ومرة أخرى، وسأسميه T2.
So let's pull from that.
إذًا فلنسحب من هذا.
And we want to join on this table down here.
ونريد الربط بهذا الجدول هنا بالأسفل.
So, we're going to join on this table down here.
حسنًا، سوف نربط على هذا الجدول بالأسفل.
And I'll just stay that's with t3.
وسيظل هذا مع t3.
So, basically this table right here is t2.
إذًا، هذا الجدول الموجود هنا هو t2.
T3 was the table that we executed earlier,
T3 كان الجدول الذي نفذناه من قبل،
and we want to join where this max sales
ونريد ربطه حيث يساوي أقصى مبيعات
is equal to the sales that we saw in that earlier table,
المبيعات التي رأيناها في هذا الجدول السابق،
and then pull both the region,
ثم نسحب المنطقة
and the rep from the join.
والمندوب من الربط.
So let's select.
حسنًا لنحدد.
And essentially it really doesn't matter where we pull the region,
وبالضرورة لا يهم أين نسحب المنطقة،
or whether we pull max sales, or total sales.
أو سواء كنا نسحب أقصى مبيعات أو إجمالي المبيعات.
The really important part here is the join portion.
والجزء المهم هنا حقًا هو جزء الربط.
So, from t2 we could pull the region name,
إذًا، من t2، يمكننا سحب اسم المنطقة،
and from t2 we could also pull the max sales,
ومن t2، يمكننا أيضًا سحب أقصى مبيعات،
and then from t3 we need to pull the rep name.
ثم من t3، نحتاج إلى سحب اسم المندوب.
I'm just going to put that first.
سأضع هذا أولًا.
Okay.
حسنًا.
So, here we have the three parts that we need to pull,
حسنًا، لدينا هنا ثلاثة أجزاء نحتاج إلى سحبها،
and then the important part here is how we join these two tables together.
ثم الجزء المهم هنا هو كيف نربط هذين الجدولين معًا.
So, we have this table up here that has the region name,
حسنًا، لدينا هذا الجدول بالأعلى هنا الذي يحتوي على اسم المنطقة،
and the max sales for a particular rep,
وأقصى مبيعات لمندوب معين،
and now essentially what we want to do is we want to join that.
وما نريد فعله بالضرورة الآن هو أننا نريد ربط هذا.
So, we want to join on the region name equal to the other region name.
حسنًا، نريد الربط عند اسم المنطقة يساوي اسم المنطقة الأخرى.
And we want the max sales in t2
ونريد أن يكون أقصى مبيعات في t2
to be equal to the total sales in t3.
مساويًا لإجمالي المبيعات في t3.
So, if the regions match then we know that we're looking at the right region.
حسنًا، إذا كانت المناطق متطابقة فإننا نعرف أننا نتفحص المنطقة الصحيحة.
And if the max sales is equal to the total sales,
وإذا كان أقصى مبيعات مساويًا لإجمالي المبيعات،
then that means that the max sales is equal
هذا يعني أن أقصى مبيعات يساوي
to the sales that we saw for a particular rep in this first table.
المبيعات التي رأيناها لمندوب معين في الجدول الأول.
So, it'll only pull essentially
حسنًا، لن يسحب ذلك إلا
the sales representatives who have sales that are equal to these amounts,
مندوبي المبيعات الذين لديهم مبيعات مساوية لهذه المبالغ،
and where they are in this region.
وتكون موجودة في هذه المنطقة.
So basically, as you can see the Southeast has the highest.
حسنًا، كما ترون يوجد في الشمال الشرقي أعلى قدر من المبيعات.
So, maybe there is somebody in the Southeast who has this.
إذًا، قد يكون هناك شخص في الشمال الشرقي قد حقق هذه
And if we didn't match on this region here,
وإذا لم نطابق هذه المنطقة هنا،
then potentially there could be multiple with the max sales that we have in the Midwest,
فمن المحتمل أن يكون هناك تعدد مع أقصى مبيعات لدينا في الغرب الأوسط،
but it's not the max for that region,
ولكن ليس الحد الأقصى لتلك المنطقة،
this is the max for that region.
فإن هذا هو الحد الأقصى لتلك المنطقة.
So, we can match on both the region and the sales amount.
إذًا، يمكننا المطابقة على المنطقة وكمية المبيعات.
Cool. So, let's go ahead and run this.
رائع. فلنتابع ونشغّل ذلك.
Okay.
حسنًا.
So, it looks like we got four results.
حسنًا، يبدو أن لدينا أربع نتائج.
We have the Southeast, the Northeast,
لدينا المنطقة الشمالية الشرقية، والجنوبية الشرقية،
the West, and the Midwest,
والغربية، والغربية الوسطى،
and nothing else is showing there.
ولا يظهر أي شيء آخر هناك.
So there are those four regions.
حسنًا توجد تلك المناطق الأربعة.
And here's essentially the max amount of sales
وهذا بالضرورة أقصى كمية للمبيعات
by a particular rep and then the name of that representative.
حسب مندوب معين ثم اسم ذلك المندوب.